Here, we have the cat object from earlier,
لدينا هنا كائن قطة من السابق،
and you can see how it has four properties: age,
ويمكنكم أن تروا أن لديه أربع خصائص وهي: العمر،
name, meow, and greet, which point to a function.
والاسم، والمواء، والترحيب الذي يشير إلى دالة.
Now, let's go ahead and add two more properties.
لنتابع الآن ونضيف خاصيتين إضافيتين.
Let's just say that this cat has a color property.
لنفترض أن كائن القطة هذا يحتوي على خاصية اللون.
I mean, give it a value of gray.
أقصد أن نعطيه القيمة رمادي.
And we can also say that this cat has a sayName property and we give this one a function.
ونفترض أيضًا أن كائن القطة هذا لديه خاصية sayName ونخصص لها دالة.
Let's go ahead and see what the new cat object looks like.
لنتابع ونرى الشكل الذي يبدو عليه كائن القطة.
I'm going to clear my console.
سأمسح وحدة التحكم لديّ.
Okay. Now, we can see that in
حسنًا. يمكننا الآن رؤية أنه
addition to the four original properties that we had in the cat object,
بالإضافة إلى الخصائص الأصلية الأربعة التي يحتوي عليها كائن القطة،
it now has a color property, gray,
يحتوي الآن على خاصية اللون، وهي رمادي،
and the sayName property,
وخاصية sayName،
which points to a function.
التي تشير إلى دالة.
Now, let's change up this cat property just a little bit.
لنغيّر الآن خاصية كائن القطة هذا قليلًا.
Let's go ahead and delete the greet property from the cat because,
لنتابع ونحذف خاصية الترحيب من كائن القطة،
of course, cats can't talk.
لأن القطط لا تتكلم بالتأكيد.
Now, if we try to invoke the greet method on this cat object,
إذا حاولنا استدعاء أسلوب الترحيب على كائن القطة هذا الآن،
we get a type error.
فسنحصل على خطأ في النوع.
Cat.greet is not a function.
Cat.greet ليس دالة.
Let's kind of see what's going on. If we access the property on its own,
دعونا نرى ما الذي سيحدث. إذا وصلنا إلى الخاصية على مسؤوليتها،
we can see that it's undefined.
يمكننا أن نرى أنها غير محددة.
It actually doesn't exist in this object anymore.
إنها في الواقع غير موجودة في هذا الكائن بعد الآن.
So, that's why you get a type error when we're trying to invoke the greet method.
لذا، إن هذا السبب وراء الحصول على خطأ في النوع عند محاولة استدعاء أسلوب التحية.
Let's check out the cat object.
لنتحقق من كائن القطة.
So, running out of space down here,
حسنًا، لقد نفدت المساحة هنا،
let's go ahead and collapse the original one
لنتابع ذلك ونطوي الكائن الأصلي
and take a look at what's going on inside the new cat object.
ونلقي نظرة على ما يحدث داخل كائن القطة الجديد.
You see that it has now five properties: age,
سترون أنه يحتوي على خمس خصائص وهي: العمر،
color, meow, name, and sayName.
واللون، والمواء، والاسم، وsayName.
Notice how the greet property is now gone because we deleted it.
لاحظوا كيفية إزالة خاصية التحية الآن لأننا حذفناها.